JUAN LEON

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL INFORMATION



juanseleon1@hotmail.com



(+57) 320 4094111



www.linkedin.com/in/juansleon/github.com/juanseleon1



EDUCATION

- Master's in Systems Engineering @ Pontifical Xaverian University | Jan 2022 - Present
- Master's in Artificial Intelligence @ Pontifical Xaverian University | Jan 2022 - Present
- Systems Engineering @ Pontifical Xaverian University | Jun 2016 - Jun 2021

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Advanced: Java [4 years], C++ [3 years], Python [2 years] **Intermediate:** SQL [2 years], Shell Scripting (Bash) [1 year], TypeScript [1 year], JavaScript [1 year], C [1 year], R [1 year]

Basic: PHP [6 months]

TECHNOLOGIES

Development

Spring, Docker, Angular, Android SDK, Git, Linux, FastAPI, Arduino

Databases

PostgreSQL, Oracle

Cloud Technologies

AWS, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: B2 (TOEFL: 107/120)

French: B1

AWARDS AND HONORS

3rd Place @ DragonJar Security Conference CTF| 20183rd Place out of 35 participants at DragonJar capture the flag competition.

Jose Gabriel Maldonado Award @ Pontifical Xaverian University | 2021

Award given to a student with excellent academic achievements and outstanding participation in social activities involving the community inside the university.

PROFILE

Dedicated and performance-driven software engineer with 2 years of experience in backend and mobile software design and development using Java, Python and C++. Solid reputation as a quick learner and a patient mentor, who's passionate about new challenges involving software development best practices, back-end technologies, artificial intelligence and robotics. Able to effectively self-manage during indepedent projects, as well as to collaborate as part of a productive team.

EXPERIENCE

Robotics Research Assistant

Pontifical Xaverian University | Feb 2022 - Sep 2022

- Designed and implemented a web-based Scratch-like block tool, named STblocks, for Arduino code generation.
- The project was developed using JavaScript, HTML, CSS for the front-end and Spring (Java 8) and Bottle (Python 3.10) for the back-end.
- Implemented a Java Library used to create and execute Petri Nets to handle concurrency and synchronization between multiple robot agents.

Associate Consultant

Oracle | Dic 2021 - Mar 2022

- Solved data migration requirements by leading the design process of a data pipeline using **Java and C macros**.
- Designed, implemented and tested billing and invoicing requirements for the client business processes.
- **Trained two interns** in basic programming skills and Oracle products fundamentals.

Freelance Software Developer

Pontifical Xaverian University | Dic 2021 - Feb 2022

- Created a **Java-based Android application (SDK 29)**, named QuycApp to handle multiple robotic actors according to the user desires.
- Designed the application following the **MVVM pattern.**
- Realized multiple user acceptance tests with users (children between 10 to 17 years).

Intern

Oracle | Dic 2020 - Dic 2021

- Implemented **REST service** customization using **Jax-rs**.
- Designed, implemented and tested **Java integration interfaces** between the client information systems and Oracle products.
- Reviewed code, ran automated memory testing and fixed identified bugs in at least 3 business process related macros.

PROJECTS

Asset Management Dashboard

EPM - Correlation One | Apr 2021 - Sep 2021

- Developed a functional data analytics dashboard for asset management and work order text mining.
- Designed and trained a NLP model using TensorFlow and Keras (80% accuracy).
- Built the backend in Python 3.9 using FastAPI framework for REST services and SQLAlchemy to handle a PostgreSQL database.
- Deployed in a **Docker** container using an **AWS EC2** instance.
- The project was adopted by EPM as part of their current data analytics processes.